Hello everyone. We are HydroSat Systems. Our Track 2 project turns multispectral satellite observations into actionable water-quality information.
大家好，我们是 HydroSat Systems。 我们的 Track 2 项目致力于把多光谱卫星观测转化为可执行的水质信息。
We approached this challenge as an onboard decision-system problem, not only as a pure regression task.
我们把这项挑战看作一个星上决策系统问题， 而不仅仅是一个纯粹的回归任务。
The question for us was: how can a satellite ingest mounted point requests and run bounded local inference
我们思考的核心问题是： 卫星如何接收挂载的点位请求，并执行受限的本地推理，
while downlinking compact turbidity and chlorophyll-a products quickly enough to support real decisions?
同时快速下传紧凑的浊度和叶绿素 a 产品， 以支持真正的决策需求？
The final architecture is modular and practical.
我们的最终架构是模块化且实用的。
First, the container reads the mounted point tables and the multispectral scene bundle.
第一步，容器读取挂载的点位表 和多光谱场景数据。
Second, it extracts a 24 by 24 local patch for each requested coordinate, so we avoid full-scene processing on the critical path.
第二步，它会围绕每个目标坐标提取一个 24×24 的局部图像块， 从而避免在关键路径上处理整景图像。
Third, we generate a large feature set with spectral bands, water indices, ratios, spatial summaries, and seasonal metadata.
第三步，我们生成大规模特征集合， 包括光谱波段、水体指数、比值、空间统计和季节性元数据。
Fourth, we run target-specific ensemble regressors, apply runtime calibration, and write the required Track 2 JSON outputs.
第四步，我们运行面向目标的集成回归器， 执行运行时校准，并写出 Track 2 要求的 JSON 输出。
We deliberately kept the default runtime CPU-first.
我们刻意将默认运行时保持为 CPU 优先。
The frozen runtime model bundle is about 4.8 megabytes, and the default path does not depend on runtime downloads or mandatory CNN inference.
冻结后的运行时模型包只有大约 4.8 MB， 默认路径也不依赖运行时下载或强制 CNN 推理。
On this local machine, the full released Area8 evaluation covers 475 points in about 25.2 seconds.
在这台本地机器上，完整的 Released Area8 评估 覆盖 475 个点，耗时约 25.2 秒。
That gives us a practical reference for execution time, artifact footprint, deployment simplicity, and a bounded, auditable satellite-ground workflow.
这为执行时间、模型体积和部署简洁性提供了实际参考， 也体现出一个受限且可审计的星地工作流。
A ground-first pattern often prioritizes sending full imagery down first and interpreting it later.
传统的地面优先模式通常会先下传整景影像， 再在地面进行解释。
Our design is different. We compute point-centered spectral-spatial descriptors and keep separate targets
我们的设计不同。 我们计算以点位为中心的光谱—空间描述符，并将两个目标分开建模，
so turbidity and chlorophyll-a can follow their own feature importance patterns, while heavier CNN work stays off the default path.
这样浊度和叶绿素 a 都可以遵循各自的特征重要性模式， 而更重的 CNN 工作则不放在默认路径上。
On top of that deployable baseline, we propose a site-adaptive layer that can use historical same-station measurements once a basin is under active monitoring.
在这个可部署基线上，我们进一步提出一个站点自适应层， 当流域进入持续监测阶段后，它可以利用同站点的历史观测。
The strongest evidence in the final repository is that we keep two questions separate.
最终仓库中最重要的证据是， 我们把两个问题清楚地区分开来。
For the frozen competition-style runtime, we use the official released Area8 evaluator and reach a reproducible algorithm score of 14.58.
对于冻结的竞赛风格运行时， 我们使用官方 Released Area8 评估器，并得到可复现的 14.58 总分。
For the stronger monitored-basin concept, post-release retrospective date-held-out research reached 53.95
对于更强的受监测流域方案， 在加入同站点时间校准后，事后回顾性的按日期留出研究得到了 53.95 分。
after adding same-site temporal calibration. The first number is leaderboard-comparable.
第一个数字是可以和排行榜比较的运行时结果， 而第二个数字并不是排行榜声明。
The second shows why the mission design is more ambitious than the frozen benchmark model alone.
它说明了为什么我们的任务设计 比冻结的基准模型本身更有雄心。
Our roadmap starts from a compact frozen baseline and a stronger adaptive direction.
我们的路线图从一个紧凑的冻结基线 和一个更强的自适应方向出发。
First, we want to productionize the site-adaptive layer with uncertainty-aware fallbacks.
第一，我们希望把站点自适应层产品化， 并加入带不确定性感知的回退机制。
Second, we want to test causal forward-only adaptation for near-real-time operations and improve turbidity robustness under shift.
第二，我们希望测试因果式、仅向前的自适应方案， 用于接近实时的运行，并提升浊度在分布偏移下的鲁棒性。
Third, we want to extend the pipeline toward regime-aware routing and selective downlink.
第三，我们希望把整套流程进一步扩展到 分层路由和选择性下传。
The important point is that the current repository is already runnable, and the roadmap builds on that instead of replacing it.
关键在于，当前仓库已经是可运行的， 路线图是在此基础上继续建设，而不是推倒重来。
HydroSat Systems is a two-person build team.
HydroSat Systems 是一个两人构建团队。
Arv Bali led the modeling direction, submission ownership, and final proposal narrative.
Arv Bali 负责建模方向、提交策略 以及最终方案叙事。
Mrinank handled evaluation tooling, late-stage experiment infrastructure, environment setup, runtime integration, and packaging.
Mrinank 负责评估工具、后期实验基础设施、 环境搭建、运行时集成和打包工作。
Together, our goal was to deliver not only a leaderboard attempt, but a compact and credible onboard inference baseline.
我们的目标不仅是做一次排行榜提交， 更是交付一个紧凑且可信的星上推理基线。
Thank you for listening. HydroSat now delivers a reproducible frozen runtime at 14.58
感谢大家的聆听。 HydroSat 现在已经提供了一个可复现的 14.58 冻结运行时基线，
and a clearer path toward site-adaptive water-quality intelligence as monitoring history accumulates.
并且随着监测历史的积累， 也展现出迈向站点自适应水质智能的更清晰路径。